Guide to the Edward G. and Hortense R. Levy Autograph Collection, Part Two
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Edward G. and Hortense R. Levy autograph collection, part two
1666-1975
OSB MSS 137
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
14.6
(38 boxes)
Consists of several thousand clipped autographs, franked envelopes, autographed photographs and printed cards and slips, and autograph notes and letters.
Levy, Edward G., 1898-1990
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Edward G. and Hortense R. Levy, 1983.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
EDWARD G. LEVY (1898-1990)
Edward G. Levy was born in New Haven, Connecticut on October 21, 1898 and educated in the city's public schools. He received his LL.B. from Boston University in 1921 and joined his brother, Herman L. Levy, in his law practice in New Haven, specializing in theatrical law. Levy married Hortense Rosenblatt in 1926; their son Charles Joseph was born in 1935.
In May 1938, Levy was charged with participating in a conspiracy with 22 others, including the Mayor of Waterbury, to defraud that city of more than $1,000,000. He pled guilty and turned state's evidence; the New York Times reported on February 4, 1939 that Levy admitted under cross-examination that he had been expelled from Yale University for cheating and that he had worked as a lobbyist "for various interests" before becoming involved with the consipirators. For his cooperation, Levy received the relatively light sentence of one year in jail.
In his later years, Levy became known as a dime novel collector and historian, and he and his wife amassed substantial autograph collections as well, donating dime novels and manuscripts to several universities, including Harvard, New York University, and Yale. The couple maintained residences in Woodbridge, Connecticut, and Palm Beach, Florida, where they were members of the Palm Beach Country Club. Edward G. Levy died on January 15th, 1990.
Scope and Contents
The Edward G. and Hortense R. Levy Collection, Part Two consists of several thousand clipped autographs, franked envelopes, autographed photographs and printed cards and slips, and autograph notes and letters. The collection spans the dates 1666-1975, but the overwhelming majority of the autographs are by nineteenth century British notables. The Levys acquired groups of autographs in occupational categories of interest to them, including artists and authors; clergy; lawyers and judges; military men; political notables; members of the British royal family and the British nobility; musicians; scientists, and theatrical figures including actors, actresses and producers. Many of the items are accompanied by their original annotated wrappers.
The collection is organized into three series: Series I, Autograph Items by Category; Series II, Uncategorized Autograph Items and Fragments; and Series III, Lists.
Actors -- Great Britain -- Autographs; Artists -- Great Britain -- Autographs; Authors, English -- Autographs; Autographs -- Great Britain; Clergy -- Great Britain -- Autographs; Gentry -- Great Britain -- Autographs; Jews -- Great Britain -- Autographs; Lawyers -- Great Britain -- Autographs; Nobility -- Great Britain -- Autographs; Politicians -- Great Britain -- Autographs; Royal family -- Great Britain -- Autographs; Scientists -- Great Britain -- Autographs; Autographs (manuscripts); Levy, Edward G., 1898-1990
- Autograph Items by Category, 1666-1961; Series I; 12.1; (32 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Autograph Files by Category, contains several thousand autographs, first alphabetically arranged by occupational group or historical subject and then alphabetically by signer's name. The group and subject categories are those used by the Levys, as are the name forms included in this list. Generally, members of the nobility are referred to by their highest titles; married women are referred to by their married names; and actors are listed under their stage names, but there are exceptions. Many individuals are represented by more than one autograph. In these cases, there are no item counts, but the date span for the contents of the folder has been given.
  - ARTISTS
    - Alma-Tadema, Laura, 1852-1909, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alma-Tadema, Lawrence, Sir, 1836-1912, 1883-1906, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Andrews, G. H., 1888, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Armitage, Edward, 1817-1896, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Armstead, Henry Hugh, 1828-1905, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Arnald, Sebastian Z., undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bacon, John H., 1865-1914, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Baily, Edward Hodges, 1788-1867, 1843-63 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bairnsfather, Bruce, b. 1887, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Barnes, Robert, 1840-1895, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Barton, Rose, 1856-1929, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bayliss, Wyke, Sir, 1835-1906, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Beverley, William Rosby, 1824-1889, 1815 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Biffin, Sarah, 1784-1850, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Birch, Charles Bell, 1832-1893, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Blackburn, Henry, 1830-1897, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Blind, Rudolph, 1850-1916, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bloomfield, Arthur William, Sir, 1829- 1899, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bodley, George Frederick, 1827-1907, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Boehm, Joseph Edgar, Sir, 1834-1890, 1879-90, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bond, William J.J.C., 1863 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bone, Henry Pierce, 1779-1855, 1844 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bone, Muirhead, Sir, 1876-1953, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Boughton, George Henry, 1834-1905, 1889-95, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Brabazon, Hercules Brabazon, 1821-1906, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bradley, Basil, 1842-1904, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Brandon, D., 1879 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Brierly, Oswald Walters, Sir, 1817- 1894, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Brock, Thomas, Sir, 1847-1922, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Brown, Ford Madox, 1821-1893, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Browne, Lennox, 1841-1902, 1883-92 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Browne, Thomas Arthur, 1870-1910, 1903-05 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Bruce, John, 1831-1893, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Bruce-Joy, A., 1844-1924, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Burne-Jones, Philip, 1861-1926, 1897, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Butler, Elizabeth, Lady, 1846-1933, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Calderon, P.H. (Philip Hermogenes), 1833-1898, 1890, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Callcott, Augustus Wall, Sir, 1779- 1844, 1840, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Cardwell, Holme, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Carrick, Thomas, 1802-1875, 1845, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Carter, William, b. 1863, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Chalon, Alfred Edward, 1780-1860, 1849, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Chalon, John James, 1778-1854, 1849, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Chantry, Francis Legatt, Sir, 1781- 1841, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Clausen, George, 1852-1944, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Cleaver, Thomas Reginald, d. 1954, 1892-97 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Clint, George, 1770-1854, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Cole, George Vicat, 1833-1893, 1876-79, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Cole, Henry, Sir, 1808-1882, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Cole, Rex Vicat, b. 1870, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Collier, John, 1850-1934, 1905, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Collins, William George, b. 1904, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Colvin, Sidney, Sir, 1845-1927, 1885-1922, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Cooke, Edward William, 1811-1880, 1861-75, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Cooke, William John, 1797-1865, 1831, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Cooper, Abraham, 1787-1868, 1830-46, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Cooper, Alfred Davis, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Cooper, Thomas Sidney, 1803-1902, 1843-97, undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Cope, Arthur Stockdale, Sir, 1857-1940, 1891-1916 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Cope, Charles West, 1811-1890, 1832-59, undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Corbould, Edward Henry, 1815-1905, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Corbould, George J., 1786-1846, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Corkran, Henriette, d. 1911, undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Costello, Louisa Stuart, 1799-1870, undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Cotman, Joseph John, 1814-1878, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Crane, Walter, 1845-1915, 1897, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Creswick, Thomas, 1811-1869, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Cruikshank, George, 1792-1878, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Cunliffe-Owen, Francis Philip, Sir, 1828-1894, 1877-86 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Cust, Lionel, 1859-1929, 1899-1913 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Dalziel, Gilbert, 1853-1930, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Davis, Henry William Banks, 1833-1914, 1863-1905, undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Davis, Richard Barrett, 1782-1854, 1834 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Deana, William Wood, 1825-1873, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Defregger, Franz von, 1835-1921, undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Deuchar, David, 1743-1808, 1784, undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Dicksee, Francis Bernard, Sir, 1853- 1928, 1883-1900 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Dillon, Frank, 1823-1909, 1865-1905 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Doo, George Thomas, 1800-1886, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Dore, Gustave, 1832-1883, undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - D'Orsay, Guillaume Gabriel, 1801-1852, undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Dow, Thomas Millie, d. 1919, undated (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Doyle, Richard, 1824-1883, undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Drury, Alfred, d. 1944, 1897-1918 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Dryden, C.B., 1796-1833, undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Duffield, Mary Elizabeth Rosenberg, 1819-1914, undated (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Duffield, W., 1816-1863, 1859, undated (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Du Maurier, George, 1834-1896, undated (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Durham, Joseph, 1814-1877, 1867, undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Earl, Maud, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - East, Alfred, 1849-1913, 1897-1902 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Eastlake, Charles Lock, Sir, 1793-1865, 1861, undated (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Eastlake, Elizabeth Rigby, Lady, 1809- 1893, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Eaton, F.A., 1880 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Eddis, Eden Upton, 1812-1901, 1853-87 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Edwards, Mary Ellen, 1830- ca. 1910, 1864, undated (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Egley, William, 1798-1870, 1838-58, undated (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Egremont, Earl, 1751-1837, 1837, undated (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Elmore, Alfred, 1815-1881, 1864-72 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Emslie, A.E., 1894 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Essex, William, 1784-1869, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Etty, William, 1787-1849, undated (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Eye, August von, 1825-1896, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Faed, Thomas, 1826-1900, 1888, undated (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Fairholt, F.W. (Frederick William), 1814-1866, 1848-50, undated (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Farmer, Emily, 1826-1905, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Felu, Charles, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Fenn, Harry, 1838-1911, undated (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Fennell, J.G. (John Greville), 1807- 1885, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Fergusson, James, 1808-1886, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Fielding, Copley, 1787-1855, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Fildes, Luke, Sir, 1844-1927, 1900-02 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Finberg, A.J. (Alexander Joseph), 1866-1939, 1903-09 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Firth, William Powell, 1819-1909, 1851-89, undated (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Ford, E. Onslow, 1852-1901, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Foster, Myles Birket, 1825-1899, 1878-99 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Fowler, Charles, 1792-1867, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Frampton, George J., Sir, 1860-1928, 1904-12 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Fripp, Alfred Downing, 1822-1895, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Fripp, George A., 1814-1896, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Frith, William Powell, 1819-1909, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Frost, William Edward, 1810-1877, 1848-58 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Fulleylove, John, 1847-1908, undated (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Furniss, Harry, 1854-1925, 1886-95 (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Furse, Charles Wellington, 1868-1904, undated (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Gale, William, 1823-1909, 1862 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Gamble-Parry, Thomas, 1816-1888, 1832-82 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Gastineau, Henry, 1791-1876, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Gaul, James J., 1887 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Geller, William Overend, undated (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Giacomelli, Hector, 1822-1904, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Gilbert, John, Sir, 1817-1897, 1883, undated (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Gleichen, Feodora, Countess, 1861-1922, 1902, undated (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Godwin, George, 1815-1888, undated (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Goodall, Frederick, 1822-1904, undated (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Goodwin, Albert, 1845-1932, 1908, undated (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Gordon, John Watson-, Sir, 1788-1864, undated (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Gotch, Thomas Cooper, 1854-1931, 1899-1902, undated (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Gould, F. Carruthers (Francis Carruthers), Sir, 1844-1925, 1901, undated (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Gow, Mary L., 1902 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Grainger, Richard, 1798-1861, 1837 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Grant, Francis, Sir, 1803-1878, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Grant, William James, 1829-1866, undated (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Grattan, Harry, undated (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Graves, Robert, 1798-1873, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Grego, Joseph, 1843-1908, 1889-90 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Greiffenhagen, Maurice, 1862-1931, 1897, undated (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Gush, William, 1878 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Gwilt, John Sebastian, 1811-1890, 1845 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Haag, Carl, 1820-1915, 1871-89, undated (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Haden, Francis Seymour, Sir, 1818-1910, undated (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Haghe, Louis, 1806-1885, 1862 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Haite, George Charles, 1855-1924, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Hale, W. Matthew, 1849-1929, 1895 (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Hall, Fitzedward, 1825-1901, 1880 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Hall, S.C. (Samuel Carter), 1800-1889, 1861, undated (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Halswelle, Keeley, 1832-1891, undated (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - Hammond, Chris, d. 1900, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - Hardy, Dudley, 1867-1922, 1890, undated (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Hardy, Frederick Daniel, 1827-1891, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Hardy, Paul, b. 1862, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Harford, J. Battersby, 1858 (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - Harrison, Charles, d. 1943, 1905, undated (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - Hassall, John, b. 1868, 1900, undated (Box 3, Folder 164)
    - Havers, Alice, 1850-1890, undated (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Haydon, S., undated (Box 3, Folder 166)
    - Hayllar, James, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 167)
    - Hayter, George, 1792-1871, 1833-50, undated (Box 3, Folder 168)
    - Hayter, John, 1800-1895, 1840, undated (Box 3, Folder 169)
    - Heaphy, Thomas, 1813-1873, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 170)
    - Heath, Charles, 1785-1848, 1818, undated (Box 3, Folder 171)
    - Hemy, Charles Napier, 1841-1917, 1895-1913 (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - Herbert, John Rogers, 1810-1890, 1844-57, undated (Box 3, Folder 173)
    - Herdman, Robert, 1829-1888, undated (Box 3, Folder 174)
    - Hering, George Edwards, 1805-1879 (Box 3, Folder 175)
    - Herkomer, Hubert von, Sir, 1849-1914, 1880-1909 (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - Heseltine, John Postle, 1845-1929, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 177)
    - Hole, William, 1847-1917, undated (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - Holl, Francis, 1815-1884, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - Holmes, George A., undated (Box 3, Folder 180)
    - Holyoake, William, 1834-1894, undated (Box 3, Folder 181)
    - Hook, James Clark, 1819-1907, 1860-97, undated (Box 3, Folder 182)
    - Hooper, William Harcourt, 1834-1912, 1904, undated (Box 3, Folder 183)
    - Horne, Herbert Percy, 1864-1916, 1903-04, undated (Box 3, Folder 184)
    - Horsley, John Callcott, 1817-1903, 1866-95, undated (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - Howard, Frank, 1805-1866, 1851, undated (Box 3, Folder 186)
    - Howard, Henry, 1769-1847, 1843 (Box 3, Folder 187)
    - Howell, John, 1788-1863, 1841 (Box 3, Folder 188)
    - Howison, William, 1798-1850, 1839 (Box 3, Folder 189)
    - Hughes, William, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 190)
    - Huish, Marcus Bourne, 1845-1921, 1887, undated (Box 3, Folder 191)
    - Hunt, William Holman, 1827-1910, undated (Box 3, Folder 192)
    - Hunter, Colin, 1841-1904, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 193)
    - Hurst, Hal, b. 1865, undated (Box 3, Folder 194)
    - Huskisson, R., undated (Box 3, Folder 195)
    - Ince, Joseph Murray, 1806-1859, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 196)
    - Jacomb Hood, G.P. (George Percy), 1857-1929, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 197)
    - Jekyll, Walter, 1887 (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - Johnson, Harry John, 1826-1884, 1864 (Box 4, Folder 199)
    - Jones, Eliza Emma, 1813-1842, undated (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - Jones, George, 1786-1869, undated (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - Jopling, Joseph Middleton, 1831-1884, 1865, undated (Box 4, Folder 202)
    - Jopling, Louise, 1843-1933, 1907-13, undated (Box 4, Folder 203)
    - Joseph, George Francis, 1764-1846, 1802 (Box 4, Folder 204)
    - Joy, Thomas Musgrave, 1812-1866, 1856 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - Judkin, T.J. (Thomas James), 1788-1871, undated (Box 4, Folder 206)
    - Jutsum, Henry, 1816-1869, 1854-62 (Box 4, Folder 207)
    - Keene, Charles, 1823-1891, undated (Box 4, Folder 208)
    - Kempe, Charles, Eamer, 1837-1907, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 209)
    - Kemp-Welch, Lucy, 1869-1958, 1904, undated (Box 4, Folder 210)
    - Kennedy, William Denholm, 1813-1865, undated (Box 4, Folder 211)
    - Kennington, T.B. d. 1916, 1893-1901 (Box 4, Folder 212)
    - King, William Thomas, undated (Box 4, Folder 213)
    - Knight, John Prescot, 1803-1881, 1848-72 (Box 4, Folder 214)
    - Laird, Miss A.H., 1849 (Box 4, Folder 215)
    - Landels, W. William, 1823-1899, 1860 (Box 4, Folder 216)
    - Landseer, Charles, 1799-1879, 1855, undated (Box 4, Folder 217)
    - Landseer, Edwin Henry, Sir, 1803-1873, 1840-60, undated (Box 4, Folder 218)
    - Landseer, Jessica, 1810-1880 (Box 4, Folder 219)
    - La Thangue, Henry Herbert, 1859-1929, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 220)
    - Lawson, F.W., 1918 (Box 4, Folder 221)
    - Leader, Benjamin Williams, 1831-1923, 1874-1900, undated (Box 4, Folder 222)
    - Lee, Frederick Richard, 1798-1879, 1851 (Box 4, Folder 223)
    - Leech, John, 1817-1864, undated (Box 4, Folder 224)
    - Legros, Alphonse, 1837-1911, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 225)
    - Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896, 1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 226)
    - Leslie, Charles Robert, 1794-1859, 1852, undated (Box 4, Folder 227)
    - Leslie, George Dunlop, 1835-1921, 1889-1908, undated (Box 4, Folder 228)
    - Lewis, John Frederick, 1805-1876, 1860, undated (Box 4, Folder 229)
    - Lewis, Lennard, b. 1826, 1882 (Box 4, Folder 230)
    - Lindsay, Coutts, Sir, 1824-1913, 1856-79 (Box 4, Folder 231)
    - Linton, James Dromgole, Sir, 1840-1916, 1882-1900, undated (Box 4, Folder 232)
    - Linton, W.J. (William James), 1812- 1897, undated (Box 4, Folder 233)
    - Logsdall, William, 1859-1944, 1905, undated (Box 4, Folder 234)
    - Lohr, Charlotte E., undated (Box 4, Folder 235)
    - Long, Edwin Longsden, 1829-1891, 1871-90, undated (Box 4, Folder 236)
    - Lorimer, John Henry, 1856-1936, undated (Box 4, Folder 237)
    - Lough, John Graham, 1806-1876, 1872 (Box 4, Folder 238)
    - Lovering, Ida, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 239)
    - Lucas, Horatio Joseph, 1839-1873, undated (Box 4, Folder 240)
    - Lucas, John, 1807-1874, undated (Box 4, Folder 241)
    - Lucas, R.W., 1839 (Box 4, Folder 242)
    - Lucy, Charles, 1814-1873, 1857, undated (Box 4, Folder 243)
    - Maclise, Daniel, 1806-1870, undated (Box 5, Folder 244)
    - MacWhirter, John, 1839-1911, undated (Box 5, Folder 245)
    - Madgwick, F., undated (Box 5, Folder 246)
    - Marks, Henry Stacy, 1829-1898, 1869-98, undated (Box 5, Folder 247)
    - Marsh, Arthur H., d. 1909, 1887 (Box 5, Folder 248)
    - Marshall, Charles, 1806-1890, 1875 (Box 5, Folder 249)
    - Marshall, Herbert (Herbert Menzies), 1841-1913, 1887-92, undated (Box 5, Folder 250)
    - Marshall, William Calder, 1813-1894, undated (Box 5, Folder 251)
    - Marston, Henry, undated (Box 5, Folder 252)
    - Martin, John, 1789-1854, 1822, undated (Box 5, Folder 253)
    - Martineau, Robert Braithwaite, 1826- 1869, undated (Box 5, Folder 254)
    - May, Phil, 1864-1903, undated (Box 5, Folder 255)
    - McConnell, William, 1878-93 (Box 5, Folder 256)
    - McLachlan, Thomas Hope, 1845-1897, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 257)
    - Meadows, Joseph Kenny, 1790-1874, undated (Box 5, Folder 258)
    - Mee, Anne, 1775-1851, 1807 (Box 5, Folder 259)
    - Merritt, Henry, 1822-1877, 1867 (Box 5, Folder 260)
    - Meyer, A. Von, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 261)
    - Miles, George Francis (Frank), 1852- 1891, undated (Box 5, Folder 262)
    - Millais, John Everett, Sir, 1829-1896, 1861-96, undated (Box 5, Folder 263)
    - Mitchell, James, 1791-1852, 1832 (Box 5, Folder 264)
    - Mogford, Thomas, 1809-1868, 1856 (Box 5, Folder 265)
    - Montalba, Clara, d.1929, 1887-99, undated (Box 5, Folder 266)
    - Montalba, Henrietta, 1856-1893, undated (Box 5, Folder 267)
    - Morris, Philip Richard, 1833-1902, 1861-92, undated (Box 5, Folder 268)
    - Morrish, W.S., 1875 (Box 5, Folder 269)
    - Moscheles, Felix, 1833-1917, 1889-1901 (Box 5, Folder 270)
    - Mossman, David, 1856 (Box 5, Folder 271)
    - Muhlenfeldt, Louisa S., undated (Box 5, Folder 272)
    - Muller, Edmund Gustavus, fl. 1836-1837, 1846-60 (Box 5, Folder 273)
    - Murden, W., 1861 (Box 5, Folder 274)
    - Murray, David, Sir, 1849-1933, 1891-1919, undated (Box 5, Folder 275)
    - Naish, J.G., undated (Box 5, Folder 276)
    - Nesfield, William Andrews, 1793-1881, 1867 (Box 5, Folder 277)
    - North, John William, 1842-1924, 1902-03 (Box 5, Folder 278)
    - O'Neil, Henry, 1817-1880, undated (Box 5, Folder 279)
    - Orchardson, William Quiller, Sir, 1832-1910, undated (Box 5, Folder 280)
    - Ottley, William Young, 1771-1836, 1831 (Box 5, Folder 281)
    - Ouless, Walter William, 1848-1933, 1879-92 (Box 5, Folder 282)
    - Paton, J. Noel (Joseph Noel), Sir, 1821-1901, 1845 (Box 5, Folder 283)
    - Patten, George, d. 1865 (Box 5, Folder 284)
    - Peacock, Ralph, 1868-1946, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 285)
    - Pennell, Elizabeth Robins, 1855-1936, 1899-1910, undated (Box 5, Folder 286)
    - Pennell, Joseph, 1857-1926, 1894-1913, undated (Box 5, Folder 287)
    - Pettie, John, 1839-1893, undated (Box 5, Folder 288)
    - Phene, J.S., 1874 (Box 5, Folder 289)
    - Philip, John, 1824-1875, undated (Box 5, Folder 290)
    - Phillip, John, 1817-1867, 1858-65, undated (Box 5, Folder 291)
    - Phillips, Claude, Sir, 1848-1924, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 292)
    - Piffard, Harold, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 293)
    - Poynter, Edward John, Sir, bart., 1836-1919, 1879-1906, undated (Box 5, Folder 294)
    - Prinsep, Valentine Cameron, 1838-1904, 1876-1900, undated (Box 5, Folder 295)
    - Reed, Edward Tennyson, 1860-1933, undated (Box 5, Folder 296)
    - Richards, William, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 297)
    - Richmond, William Blake, Sir, 1842- 1921, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 298)
    - Russell, J. Scott (John Scott), 1808- 1882, 1852 (Box 5, Folder 299)
    - Sant, James, 1820-1916, 1910-15 (Box 5, Folder 300)
    - Smith, E.D., undated (Box 5, Folder 301)
    - Swallow, John Charles, fl. 1858-1876, 1877 (Box 5, Folder 302)
    - Swan, John Macallan, 1847-1910, 1887-1906, undated (Box 5, Folder 303)
    - Tayler, Frederick, 1802-1889, 1849-59 (Box 5, Folder 304)
    - Thomas, John, 1818-1862, 1851-55 (Box 5, Folder 305)
    - Thomas, W. Cave (William Cave), b. 1820, 1889 (Box 5, Folder 306)
    - Thornycroft, William Hamo, Sir, 1850- 1925, 1891-1916 (Box 5, Folder 307)